

NIKHIL MATA

Pune | 8793226225 | <u>nikhilmata47@gmail.com</u> | 09 January, 1994

ABOUT ME

I am enrolled with the Bar Council of India. I have relevant work experience in litigation as well as corporate practice. My work experience till date has trained me to independently handle litigation pertaining to trademark, copyright infringement, civil disputes, money recovery cases, insolvency proceedings under IBC, cases under Negotiable Instruments Act, economic offences and consumer disputes. My interest also lies in corporate transactions, commercial disputes and drafting of corporate-commercial contracts. With my work experience in various fields of Law, I have gained equal knowledge and practical experience in litigation and non-litigation matters.

EDUCATION

First Class LLB

Shri Nathmal Goenka Law College, Akola, Sant Gadge Baba Amravati University,

Amravati.

First Class B.Com

Smt Laxmibai Radhakisan Toshniwal College of, Commerce, Akola, Sant Gadge Baba

Amravati, University, Amravati.

First Class HSC 12th

Smt Laxmibai Radhakisan Toshniwal College of Commerce, Akola, Sant Gadge Baba Amravati, University, Amravati.

Second Class

SSC 10th

Hindu Dnyanpeeth Convent School, Akola.

WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2019 to Present Legal & Administrative Head

Onus Design

- Drafting and vetting of supply agreement, purchase agreement, loan agreement, master service agreement, along with litigation related documents such as various applications, civil suits, criminal complaints, legal notices etc. required in civil and corporate-commercial disputes.
- Communicate with their clients, colleagues, and others involved in the case.
- Present facts in writing and verbally to their clients or others, and argue on behalf of their clients.
- Prepare and file legal documents, such as lawsuits, appeals, wills, contracts, and deeds.
- Oversee the work of support staff, such as paralegals and legal assistants and legal secretaries and junior advocate.
- Legal writing and research for legal articles for the Firm.

March 2018-April 2019 Associate Advocate

Rishabh Gandhi and Advocates, Pune

- Drafting and vetting of corporate-commercial contracts such as slump-sale agreement, business transfer agreement, asset purchase agreement, arbitration agreement, loan agreement, master service agreement, IP agreement, hire-purchase agreement, along with litigation related documents such as various applications, civil suits, criminal complaints, legal notices etc. required in civil and corporate-commercial disputes.
- Representing clients in civil, consumer, criminal, property litigation matters and appearance before Civil Courts, Consumer Courts, Criminal Courts in Pune.
- Filing of complaints under RERA & MAHARERA, and drafting of real estate and construction agreements and contracts.
- Representing clients before the NCLT in insolvency and bankruptcy proceedings and before the Trademark Registry in objection and oppositions. Drafting and filing of Insolvency Notice and petitions before the NCLT.
- Representing clients before the Civil Courts in trademark infringement suits, drafting and filing of trademark and copyright applications before the Trademark Registry.
- Representing individuals in matrimonial cases of divorce, maintenance, custody, restitution of conjugal rights, domestic violence, cruelty, and also advising in drafting of wills, adoption

deed and obtaining heirship and succession certificates etc.

 Legal writing and research for legal articles for the Firm.

June 2017-Feb-2018 *Junior Advocate*

Kotwani and Associates, Akola

- Representing clients in civil, consumer, criminal, property litigation matters and appearances before Civil Courts, Consumer Courts, Labour Courts, and Criminal Courts in Akola.
- Drafting of plaints, civil suits, criminal complaints, legal notices etc. required in civil and criminal disputes.

INTERNSHIPS

Feb 2016-Feb 2017 Intern

Adv. Satish Kotwani, Akola

Assisted in drafting and research for cases falling under criminal law and civil law, and gained practical experience of criminal and civil cases pending before the courts.

Jan-Feb 2015 Intern

Adv. Garima Gupta, Delhi

 Assisted in drafting court applications and notices for cases falling under criminal and civil laws. Research work under Civil Procedure Code,1908 Negotiable Instruments Act, 1881.

July 2009-Dec 2012

Admin & Accounts Executive

M/s S.J. and Sons

- Carried out administrative work, day to day operations and client management of the Firm.
- Assisted in accounting and finance of the Firm.
- My responsibilities also included reviewing and reconciling accounts, book-keeping, updating internal accounting databases and spreadsheets, processing payments to external partners and maintaining updated records of invoices, receipts and inventory control.

PRO BONO WORK

Through pro bono work, I intend to fulfill my responsibility towards the society at large and I am directly involved with charity and community work. I also provide legal aid to local NGOs.